<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: sketch | Syntax Error]]></title>
  <link href="http://andreamazz.github.io/blog/categories/sketch/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andreamazz.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-04T11:03:00+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://andreamazz.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrea Mazzini]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[andrea@fancypixel.it]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Small updates]]></title>
    <link href="http://andreamazz.github.io/blog/2015/01/26/small-updates/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-26T20:57:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://andreamazz.github.io/blog/2015/01/26/small-updates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m about to close week 4 of the &ldquo;One icon a day&rdquo; challenge, sometimes it&rsquo;s fun, sometimes it&rsquo;s tough, but I&rsquo;m glad I started this project. Adding some spice to the mix I also started recording what I do, mistakes and brain farts included. You can find the videos in this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL9N7C4VLxpJWOW8Au9VZyVXcR1lRFnMKD">Youtube playlist</a>.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>Speaking of icons, a Reddit user suggested to put the resulting icons on <a href="http://thenounproject.com/">the NounProject</a>. I should have thought about this before, I mean, I really wish I thought about this before, because they have some requirements that differ a bit from what I&rsquo;ve been doing. No strokes for starters, which sucks since I&rsquo;ve been using them like it&rsquo;s my job. Other than that, it&rsquo;s gonna be <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QetvK6ldl2s">smooth sailing</a>.</p>

<h2>Being a developer</h2>

<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about writing code for a while.<br/>
I took a pause from iOS in the past few months, I&rsquo;m not happy about it, but to face some pressing matters I had to put my web developer&rsquo;s clothes on.
In the end, I&rsquo;m glad, since I had a chance to choose and tinker with new stuff. First of all, I took the full API backed frontend route, using <a href="https://github.com/rails-api/rails-api">rails-api</a> (a stripped down version of Rails) to provide data for a React web app, implemented with a vanilla Flux architecture.</p>

<p>React and Flux are the new kids on the block, the documentation and community are still almost a work in progress, and there are little to no patterns to follow, even for the most trivial stuff as performing async requests or authenticating a user.
I scratched my head for a while, but in the end I&rsquo;ve learned quite a bit, and I&rsquo;m liking this new way of writing frontend apps more and more every day.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m planning on writing all down in an article in the next few days, covering all: setup, the Flux architecture, authenticating the user with a token, performing async requests.<br/>
Until next time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing an Icon a Day: Week 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://andreamazz.github.io/blog/2015/01/07/designing-an-icon-a-day-week-1/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-07T16:34:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://andreamazz.github.io/blog/2015/01/07/designing-an-icon-a-day-week-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Week 1 over for this challenge. So far so good, the commitment required seems bearable, and to be honest it&rsquo;s a great way to take the mind off the other stuff.
I&rsquo;m still not sure about the general style of the icons though. So far I opted for large icons, with a fair amount of details, outlined with two possible stroke widths (4px and 2px). I&rsquo;m not sure about this, they might look good on a landing page or a dashboard, but they&rsquo;ll probably look off on a smaller scale in an app.<br/>
I&rsquo;m probably going to switch style the next month or further up down the road, but for now, they&rsquo;ll do.</p>

<p>Until next time</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Designing an icon a day]]></title>
    <link href="http://andreamazz.github.io/blog/2014/12/16/new-years-resolution/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-16T14:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://andreamazz.github.io/blog/2014/12/16/new-years-resolution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>&ldquo;This year is the year. The year when I actually take my new year&rsquo;s resolution to its completion&rdquo;</em>. That&rsquo;s what I tell myself every year. Last year I started a new resolution: post an article a month on this blog. Well&hellip; that went great as you can see, although it was a nice experience being on the first page of <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8010233">Hacker News</a> for a brief period. <!-- More -->
I did try my best, but sometimes life hits you like a ton of bricks. Feeling swarmed I opted to dedicate my spare time to my open source projects on <a href="https://github.com/andreamazz">Github</a>, leaving this blog rather sad and empty.<br/>
Anyway, since I&rsquo;m a creature of habit, I am here telling myself <em>&ldquo;This year is the year. the year when I actually take my new year&rsquo;s resolution to its completion&rdquo;</em>. Since I&rsquo;m an idiot I&rsquo;m about to pick a challenge worth 365 daily efforts instead of 12 monthly ones.
Before illustrating this year&rsquo;s challenge, I&rsquo;ll take a step back to explain my reasoning behind this. If you happened to read one of my previous post you might know that I&rsquo;m an iOS developer at heart, and sometimes I take a stab at UI design and Rails development. I feel like my iOS tools are moderately sharp (although I need to catch up on WatchKit and start taking Swift more seriously, i.e.: start using it for production code), unlike my designer&rsquo;s skills, that definitely need some polish. That&rsquo;s why this year&rsquo;s resolution will be covered by my favorite design tool, <a href="http://bohemiancoding.com/sketch/">Sketch</a>.</p>

<h2>Designing an icon a day</h2>

<p>The other day I stumbled upon <a href="http://sensibleworld.com/news/year-of-icons/">this project</a>. A really simple idea (to describe): design an icon a day. I love this concept, for one I&rsquo;ll be able to practice designing vector shapes, and as icing on this slowly baked cake I&rsquo;ll end up with a bunch of (hopefully) reusable icons.
I was intrigued, so intrigued that I think this will be the perfect year-long project.
I can already hear future-me screaming in pain, calling me an idiot. Brilliant.</p>

<h2>How and where</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ll be using Sketch, and my main source of inspiration will be, at first, random words from a word generator.
I&rsquo;ll be posting the icons on my Github&rsquo;s profile, in <a href="https://github.com/andreamazz/one-icon-a-day">this repository</a>. The icons will be licensed under Creative Commons&rsquo;s Attribution 4.0 International licence.
The fun starts on January 1 2015. Future-me will hopefully stop this project on December 31 2015 maintaining a sizeable amount of sanity.</p>

<p>Untile next time.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m so going to botch this&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
